<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="gbm_buffer_backend">

  <copyright>
    Copyright (c) 2017, The Linux Foundation. All rights reserved.

    Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
    modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are
    met:
    * Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.
    * Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above
    copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following
    disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided
    with the distribution.
    * Neither the name of The Linux Foundation nor the names of its
    contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived
    from this software without specific prior written permission.

    THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED
    WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF
    MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT
    ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT OWNER OR CONTRIBUTORS
    BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR
    CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF
    SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR
    BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY,
    WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE
    OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN
    IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.

    Copyright (c) 2014, 2015 Collabora, Ltd.

    Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute, and sell this
    software and its documentation for any purpose is hereby granted
    without fee, provided that the above copyright notice appear in
    all copies and that both that copyright notice and this permission
    notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name of
    the copyright holders not be used in advertising or publicity
    pertaining to distribution of the software without specific,
    written prior permission.  The copyright holders make no
    representations about the suitability of this software for any
    purpose.  It is provided "as is" without express or implied
    warranty.

    THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS
    SOFTWARE, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND
    FITNESS, IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
    SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES
    WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN
    AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION,
    ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF
    THIS SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="gbm_buffer_backend" version="1">
    <description summary="GBM buffer backend support">
    This factory interface used to create wl_buffer from given GBM buffer.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="unbind the factory">
        Destroy the protocol object created at client.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="create_params">
      <description summary="create a temporary object for buffer parameters">
        This temporary object is used to hold gbm_buffer_params as
        a single batch to create a wl_buffer.It can only be used once and
        should be destroyed after an 'created' or 'failed' event has been
        received.
      </description>
      <arg name="params_id" type="new_id" interface="gbm_buffer_params"
           summary="the new temporary"/>
    </request>

  </interface>

  <interface name="gbm_buffer_params" version="1">
    <description summary="parameters for creating a gbmbuf-based wl_buffer">
      This temporary object is a collection of dmabufs and other
      parameters that together form a single logical buffer. The temporary
      object may eventually create one wl_buffer unless cancelled by
      destroying it before requesting 'create'.

      Single-planar formats only require one dmabuf, however
      multi-planar formats may require more than one dmabuf. For all
      formats, 'add' request must be called once per plane (even if the
      underlying dmabuf fd is identical).

      You must use consecutive plane indices ('plane_idx' argument for 'add')
      from zero to the number of planes used by the drm_fourcc format code.
      All planes required by the format must be given exactly once, but can
      be given in any order. Each plane index can be set only once.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="delete this object, used or not">
        Cleans up the temporary data sent to the server for dmabuf-based
        wl_buffer creation.
      </description>
    </request>

    <enum name="flags">
      <entry name="y_invert" value="1" summary="contents are y-inverted"/>
      <entry name="interlaced" value="2" summary="content is interlaced"/>
      <entry name="bottom_first" value="4" summary="bottom field first"/>
    </enum>

    <request name="create">
      <description summary="create a wl_buffer from the given gbmbufs">
        This asks for creation of a wl_buffer from the added gbmbuf
        buffers. The wl_buffer is not created immediately but returned via
        the 'created' event if the gbmbuf sharing succeeds. The sharing
        may fail at runtime for reasons a client cannot predict, in
        which case the 'failed' event is triggered.

        The 'format' argument is a DRM_FORMAT code, as defined by the
        libdrm's drm_fourcc.h. The Linux kernel's DRM sub-system is the
        authoritative source on how the format codes should work.

        The 'flags' is a bitfield of the flags defined in enum "flags".
        'y_invert' means the that the image needs to be y-flipped.

        Flag 'interlaced' means that the frame in the buffer is not
        progressive as usual, but interlaced. An interlaced buffer as
        supported here must always contain both top and bottom fields.
        The top field always begins on the first pixel row. The temporal
        ordering between the two fields is top field first, unless
        'bottom_first' is specified. It is undefined whether 'bottom_first'
        is ignored if 'interlaced' is not set.

      </description>
      <arg name="fd" type="fd" summary="ion lib based fd"/>
      <arg name="meta_fd" type="fd" summary="ion lib based meta_fd"/>
      <arg name="width" type="uint" summary="base plane width in pixels"/>
      <arg name="height" type="uint" summary="base plane height in pixels"/>
      <arg name="format" type="uint" summary="DRM_FORMAT code"/>
      <arg name="flags" type="int" summary="see enum flags"/>
    </request>

    <event name="created">
      <description summary="buffer creation succeeded">
        This event indicates that the attempted buffer creation was
        successful. It provides the new wl_buffer referencing the dmabuf(s).

        Upon receiving this event, the client should destroy the
        zlinux_dmabuf_params object.
      </description>
      <arg name="buffer" type="new_id" interface="wl_buffer"
           summary="the newly created wl_buffer"/>
    </event>

    <event name="failed">
      <description summary="buffer creation failed">
        This event indicates that the attempted buffer creation has
        failed. It usually means that one of the dmabuf constraints
        has not been fulfilled.

        Upon receiving this event, the client should destroy the
        zlinux_buffer_params object.
      </description>
    </event>

  </interface>

</protocol>
